--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制: 暮雨潇潇   字幕调校：九天     招募Q号: 76846146
快点
Hurry!
你们还不明白吗？氪星的核心正在坍塌
Do you not understand? Krypton's core is collapsing.
我们也许只剩几个星期了 我警告过你们
We may only have a matter of weeks. I warned you.
开发核心的能源与自杀无异
Harvesting the core was suicide. It has accelerated...
- 内爆的速度已经加快   - 我们的能源储备已经耗尽
- ...the process of implosion.       - Our energy reserves...
我们还能怎么办 艾尔
...were exhausted. What would you have us do, El?
像我们的祖先一样 放眼宇宙
Look to the stars, like our ancestors did.
适合居住的世界触手可及 我们可以先用那些旧前哨站
There are habitable worlds within reach. We can begin by using the old outposts.
你真的想要撤离全星球的人吗？
Are you seriously suggesting that we evacuate the entire planet?
不 我们已经救不了这里的人们了
No. Everybody here is already dead.
把密典交给我 我保证让我们种族存活下去
Give me control of the Codex. I will ensure the survival of our race.
还有希望
There is still hope.
我将这个希望握在了我的手心
I have held that hope in my hands.
长老会已经解散了
This council has been disbanded.
谁下的命令？
On whose authority?
我
Mine.
其余的人将被审判 并酌情处罚
The rest of you will be tried and punished accordingly.
- 你在干什么 佐德？你疯了   - 我几年前就该动手了
- What are you doing, Zod? This is madness.       - What I should have done years ago...
是这些立法者和他们无休止的争论毁了氪星
These lawmakers with their endless debates have lead Krypton to ruin.
就算你的军队胜利了
And if your forces prevail...
- 你也只能是个光杆司令   - 那就加入我的行列吧
- ...you'll be the leader of nothing.       - Then join me.
协助我拯救我们的种族 我们重新开始
Help me save our race. We'll start anew.
将让我们沦落到如此田地的堕落血脉切断
We'll sever the degenerative bloodlines that led us to this state.
谁来决定谁去谁留 佐德？
And who will decide which bloodlines survive, Zod?
你吗？
You?
别这样 艾尔
Don't do this, El.
我最不愿意看到的 就是我们反目成仇
The last thing I want is for us to be enemies.
你背弃了我们相约立下的原则
You have abandoned the principles that bound us together.
你将剑指向了自己的人民
You've taken up the sword against your own people.
我敬重的是曾经的你 佐德
I will honor the man you once were, Zod...
而不是如今这个禽兽
...not this monster you've become.
把他带走
Take him away.
主人 一切是否安好？
Sir? Is everything all right?
让开
Out of the way.
我再说一遍
I said...
叫莱拉过来
Get me Lara.
乔 注意身后
Jor. Behind you.
莱拉 准备好发射
Lara, you have to ready the launch.
我会尽快跟你会合
I'll be with you as soon as I can.
赫拉卡
H'Raka!
- 能看到密典吗？ - 就在中枢的下方 主人
- Can you see the Codex?        - It's just beneath the central hub.
但我不得不警告您
But I'm compelled to warn you.
入侵始源室是B级犯罪
Breaching the genesis chamber is a Class-B crime...
没人在乎这个了 基列克斯 这个世界就要毁灭了
Nobody cares anymore, Kelex. The world is about to come to an end.
乔•艾尔 佐德将军有令
Jor-El, by the authority of General Zod...
交出密典
...surrender the Codex.
坚持住 赫拉卡
Easy, H'Raka.
你们找到了那个世界吗？
Did you find a world?
- 找到了   - 它绕着一颗黄色主序星运行
- We have.        - Orbiting a main sequence yellow star...
正如您所说
...just as you said it would.
这是颗年轻的恒星
A young star.
他的细胞能吸收它的辐射能
His cells will drink its radiation.
似乎是智能生物
It's a seemingly intelligent population.
他会被遗弃
He'll be an outcast.
被当成怪物
A freak.
他会被杀掉的
They'll kill him.
不
How?
他会被当成上帝
He'll be a god to them.
如果飞船到不了那里怎么办？
What if the ship doesn't make it?
他会死在外面
He'll die out there...
孤苦伶仃地
...alone.
我做不到
I can't do it.
我以为可以 但...
I thought I could, but...
- 莱拉    - 他就在我眼前
- Lara.         - ...now that he's here...
氪星已经不行了
Krypton is doomed.
这是他唯一的机会
It's his only chance now.
这是我们民族唯一的希望
It's our people's only hope.
怎么了 基列克斯？
What is it, Kelex?
有五艘攻击舰正从东面靠近
Five attack ships converging from the east.
他们正在扫描并评估城堡的防御系统
Citadel's defenses are being scanned and evaluated.
我来上传密典
I'll upload the Codex.
不 等等
No, wait.
莱拉
Lara.
让我再看看他
Just let me look at him.
我们没机会看他走路的样子
We'll never get to see him walk.
没机会听他喊爸爸妈妈
Never hear him say our names.
他会在
But out there...
茫茫宇宙间
...amongst the stars...
活下来
...he will live.
再见  儿子
Goodbye, my son.
我们的希望与梦想与你同行
Our hopes and dreams travel with you.
向主门集中火力
Concentrate fire on the main doors.
莱拉夫人
Lady Lara.
- 幽灵引擎已启动   - 点火
- The phantom drives are coming online.       - Proceed to ignition.
将军
General.
城堡内有引擎启动
We have identified an engine ignition within the citadel.
是航天器发射
A launch.
守住这平台 指挥官
Hold this platform, commander.
我知道你偷了密典 乔•艾尔
I know you stole the Codex, Jor-El.
把它交出来
Surrender it...
我就饶你不死
...and I'll let you live.
这次重生的机会属于氪星所有人
This is a second chance for all of Krypton...
而不仅仅是你觉得重要的血脉
...not just the bloodlines you deem worthy.
你做了什么事？
What have you done?
我们有一个孩子 佐德
We've had a child, Zod.
一个男孩
A boy child.
他是氪星几百年来第一个自然分娩的孩子
Krypton's first natural birth in centuries.
他将获得自由
And he will be free.
决定自己命运的自由
Free to forge his own destiny.
胡说八道
Heresy.
把它毁了
Destroy it.
莱拉
Lara...
听我说
...listen to me.
密典是氪星的未来
The Codex is Krypton's future.
取消发射
Abort the launch.
不
No!
莱拉
Your son, Lara...
你把你们的儿子送到哪里去了？
...where have you sent him?
他的名字
His name...
是卡尔
...is Kal...
艾尔之子
...son of El.
你休想找到他
And he's beyond your reach.
把那艘飞船打下来
Bring that ship down.
目标已锁定
Target locked.
放下你们的武器
Lay down your weapons.
你们已经被包围了
Your forces are surrounded.
佐德将军
General Zod...
你犯下了谋杀罪与叛国罪
...for the crimes of murder and high treason...
长老会判处你和你的同谋
...the Council has sentenced you and your fellow insurgents...
囚禁肉身并流放300年
...to three hundred cycles of somatic reconditioning.
有什么遗言吗？
Do you have any last words?
你们不敢亲手杀我们
You won't kill us yourself!
怕弄脏了自己的手 所以你们...
You wouldn't sully your hands! But you'll damn us...
把我们扔到黑洞里关一辈子
...to a black hole for eternity!
乔•艾尔说得没错
Jor-El was right.
你们是一群蠢货 所有人都是
You're a pack of fools, every last one of you.
你
And you.
你觉得你的儿子很安全吗？
You believe your son is safe?
我一定会找到他
I will find him.
夺回你从我们手里抢走的东西
I will reclaim what you have taken from us.
我一定会找到他
I will find him.
我一定会找到他 莱拉
I will find him, Lara.
我一定会找到他
I will find him!
啊
Argh!
莱拉夫人 您不躲起来吗？
Lady Lara, shouldn't you find refuge?
根本无处可躲 基洛尔
There is no refuge, Kelor.
乔•艾尔说得对
Jor-El was right.
氪星的末日到了
This is the end.
创造一个比这里好的世界 卡尔
Make a better world than ours, Kal.
当心点 蠢货
Watch it, dumb-ass!
不留心就等着被砸成肉饼吧
Keep your eyes open or you're gonna get squashed.
他们是在什么鬼地方找到你的 菜鸟？
Where the hell did they find you, greenhorn?
让我们在空中弄掉这个陷阱
Let's get this trap in the air.
大家固定好甲板
Gentlemen, secure the deck.
正西方向的钻井处有人向我们求救
We just got a distress call from a rig due west of us.
固定好甲板
Secure the deck.
请所有民用船只离开
All civilian boats, stand clear.
海下阀门已失效 钻台快要爆炸了
The sub-sea valves failed and the rig is about to explode.
收到 海岸警卫队 被困在里面的人怎么办？
Roger, Coast Guard. What about the men left inside?
- 别管他们了 他们活不了   - 菜鸟
- Forget them. They're dead.        - Greenhorn...
把我的望远镜拿来
...fetch me my binoculars.
菜鸟
Greenhorn.
就剩这点氧气了 我不知道我们还能撑多久
This is the last of the oxygen. I don't know how much longer we can hold out.
这里是海岸警卫队6510
This is Coast Guard 6510.
我们再查看一遍 然后就离开
We'll make one more pass then get out.
等等 等等 有人在直升机升降处
Wait, wait. I got some guys on the helipad.
就在这里
Right here!
快点 走啊
Come on, come on! Let's go! Let's go!
- 快走   - 走啊
- Let's go!       - Let's go!
叫最后那个人上来
Get that last guy loaded.
我们得走了
We have got to go.
快走啊 你在干什么？
Hey, let's go. What are you doing?
走 走
Go! Go!
堪萨斯州是什么时候变成美国领土的？
...when Kansas became a territory?
克拉克
Clark.
你在听课吗 克拉克？
Are you listening, Clark?
告诉我 谁最先在堪萨斯州定居
I asked if you could tell me who first settled Kansas.
你没事吧 克拉克？
Are you all right, Clark?
克拉克
Clark.
Clark!
克拉克 出来
Clark, come out of there.
别管我
Leave me alone.
克拉克 我已经给你妈妈打电话了
Clark, I have called your mother.
克拉克
Clark?
啊
Ah!
我来了
I'm here.
克拉克 宝贝 我是妈妈
Clark, honey, it's Mom.
开门好吗？
Will you open the door?
- 他到底有什么毛病？ - 他就是个怪胎
- What's wrong with him?       - He's such a freak.
娘们
Crybaby.
他父母甚至不让我跟他玩
His parents won't even let him play with other kids.
我知道
I know.
宝贝
Sweetie.
你不让我进去 我怎么帮你？
How can I help you if you won't let me in?
这个世界太大了 妈妈
The world's too big, Mom.
那就把它变小点
Then make it small.
只要...
Just, um...
集中精力听我的声音
...focus on my voice.
想象有一座岛屿
Pretend ifs an island...
它就在大海之中
...out in the ocean.
能看到吗？
Can you see it?
我看到了
I see it.
那就向它游过去 宝贝
Then swim towards it, honey.
我怎么了 妈妈？
What's wrong with me, Mom?
克拉克
Clark.
- 你拿到我要的东西了？   - 是的
- Did you get everything I need?       - Yep.
别动 别动
Hold it, hold it.
蠢蛋
Hey, ass-wipe.
你觉得怎样？你看了比赛吗？
What do you think? You see the game?
- 别耍他 皮特   - 你算哪根葱 他的女朋友吗？
- Leave him alone, Pete.       - What are you, his girlfriend?
我要听听他怎么说
I wanna hear what he has to say.
说话啊
Come on...
笨瓜
...dick-splash.
我儿子就在现场
My son was there.
他就在那辆校车里
He was in the bus.
- 亲眼看见克拉克做了什么   - 我知道他看见了
- He saw what Clark did.       - I know he did.
- 他看到的一定是...   - 是上帝的安排 乔纳森
- I'm sure what he thought he saw was...       - Was an act of God, Jonathan.
是天意
This was providence.
我觉得你这样说有点夸张
I think you're blowing it out of proportion.
我没夸张 拉娜也看见了
No, I'm not. Lana saw it too.
那个叫福特曼的男孩也看见了
And the Fordham boy.
这也不是第一次
This isn't the first time...
克拉克做出这种事了
...Clark's done something like this.
我只是想帮忙
I just wanted to help.
我知道 但我们谈过这个了
I know you did, but we talked about this.
对吧？
Right?
对吧 我们谈过了 你...
Right? We talked about this. You have...
克拉克 你不能让别人知道你的这一面
Clark, you have to keep this side of yourself a secret.
那我该怎么办？看着他们死掉吗？
What was I supposed to do? Just let them die?
也许吧
Maybe.
危在旦夕的不只是我们的性命 克拉克
There's more at stake here than just our lives, Clark,
也不只是我们周围人的性命
or the lives of those around us.
如果这个世界
When the world...
知道了你的能力 一切都将改变 包括我们的...
When the world finds out what you can do it's gonna change everything. Our...
我们的信仰...
Our beliefs, our notions of...
对人类的概念 一切
...what it means to be human. Everything.
你看到了皮特妈妈的反应吧？
You saw how Pete's mom reacted, right?
她很害怕 克拉克
She was scared, Clark.
为什么？
Why?
人们害怕他们不了解的东西
People are afraid of what they don't understand.
她说得对吗？
Is she right?
是上帝把我变成这样的吗？
Did God do this to me?
告诉我
Tell me.
你是我们在这个东西里找到的
We found you in this.
我们以为政府一定会来找我们
We were sure the government was gonna show up on our doorstep...
但一直没人来
...but no one ever came.
这个和你一样 也是在里面找到的
This was in that chamber with you.
我把它拿给堪萨斯州的一个冶金学家看
I took it to a metallurgist at Kansas State.
他说 制成它的材料甚至...
He said whatever it was made from didn't even...
甚至不存在于元素周期表上
Didn't even exist on the periodic table.
意思是说
That's another way of saying...
它不来自于这个世界 克拉克
...that it's not from this world, Clark.
你也一样
And neither are you.
你就是答案 儿子
You're the answer, son.
"人类是否孤独地存在于宇宙中"的答案
You're the answer to "Are we alone in the universe?"
我不想当这个答案
I don't wanna be.
我不怪你 儿子
And I don't blame you, son.
一般人难以背负这种重担
It'd be a huge burden for anyone to bear.
但你不是一般人 克拉克 而且我必须相信你
But you're not just anyone, Clark, and I have to believe that you were...
你被送来这里是有原因的
That you were sent here for a reason.
你所经历的这些改变 终有一天...
All these changes that you're going through, one day...
你会觉得它们是上帝的恩赐 当那一天到来...
One day you're gonna think of them as a blessing. When that day comes...
你就必须作出选择
...you have to make a choice.
是否要在人类面前骄傲地挺身而出
A choice of whether to stand proud in front of the human race or not.
我就不能继续假装是您的儿子吗？
Can't I just keep pretending I'm your son?
你就是我儿子
You are my son.
但在某个地方
But somewhere out there you've...
你还有另外一个父亲 他给了你另外一个名字
You have another father too, who gave you another name.
出于某种原因 他把你送到了这里
And he sent you here for a reason, Clark.
就算要花一辈子的时间 你也要为自己...
And even if it takes you the rest of your life, you owe it to yourself...
找到那个原因
...to find out what that reason is.
被狂热的欲望所束缚
Bound by wild desire
我掉进了火圈
I fell into a ring of fire
等一下 你来这儿不是为了锻炼？
Wait a second. Aren't you here for the exercise?
不 那是在改变计划
No, there was a change in the plans.
听说有人在埃尔斯米尔找到些奇怪的东西
Somebody found something strange on Ellesmere.
空中侦察机已经在那里飞了一个星期
Aircom's making runs out there all week.
那个老鼠洞吗？
That rat hole?
- 你开玩笑的吧   - 不可思议 对吧
- You gotta be kidding me.       - I know. It's crazy.
许多美国人也去了那里
The Americans are there too, lots of them.
还有别的吗？他们管它叫异常物体
Anything else? They're calling it an anomalous object.
- 也不知道什么意思   - 走开 拉德洛 我认真的
- Whatever that means.       - Back off, Ludlow. I'm serious.
- 别介 克丽茜   - 住手
- Oh, come on, Chrissy.       - Knock it off.
- 坐下   - 放我走
- Sit down.       - Let me go.
放开她 哥们
Hey. Leave her alone, man.
不放又怎样 硬汉？
Or what, tough guy?
不放就只能请你离开了
Or I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
我觉得我想走的时候才会走
I think I'll probably just leave when I'm good and ready.
来劲了吗？
Oh, there he is.
犯不上 亲爱的
It's not worth it, sweetie.
混蛋 别忘了你的小费
Hey, asshole, don't forget your tip.
去吧
Strike.
谢谢
Thanks.
嗨
Hi.
莲恩小姐 你好吗？
Miss Lane. How you doing?
- 你好   - 我是杰德•尤班克斯 来自北极货运
- Good.       - Jed Eubanks, Arctic Cargo.
这离驻地有多远？
How far to the station?
- 宿营地就在上面 我陪你走过去   - 太好了
- Camp's just over the rise. I'll walk you over.       - Great.
乔可以帮你拿包 乔
Joe can take your bags. Joe.
来帮帮忙
Help her out.
小心点 那些东西很重
Careful with those. They're heavy.
我得承认 莲恩小姐
I gotta confess, Miss Lane...
我不是《星球日报》的忠实观众
...I'm not a fan of the Daily Planet.
但你潜入第一师时写的那些文章都...
But those pieces you wrote when you were embedded with the 1st Division were...
让我印象十分深刻
Well, they were pretty impressive.
我能说什么呢？不穿军服的时候我就得写专栏
Well, what can I say? I get writer's block if I'm not wearing a flak jacket.
莲恩小姐
Miss Lane.
我是美国北方司令部的哈迪上校
I'm Colonel Hardy, U.S. Northcom.
这位是高级研究计划局的埃米尔博士
Dr. Emil Hamilton from DARPA.
- 你来早了   - 嗨
- You're early.       - Hi.
我们以为你明天才到
We were expecting you tomorrow.
所以我才今天来的
Which is why I showed up today.
我们有句话得说在前头 好吗？
Look, let's get one thing straight, guys, okay?
我在这的唯一原因是
The only reason I'm here is
我们在加拿大国境内受理上诉的法庭
because we're on Canadian soil...
驳回了你们赶我走的禁令
...and the appellate court overruled your injunction to keep me away.
那么 你如果玩蛋玩够了
So if we're done measuring dicks...
能派人带我看看你们的发现吗？
...can you have your people show me what you found?
美国航空航天局的紧急救援卫星首先发现异常
NASA's EOS satellites pinged the anomaly first.
冰架的回声探测显示很混乱
The ice shelf plays hell on the echo soundings.
但那里绝对有东西
But there's something there.
说不定是苏联时代的潜艇呢？
A submarine, maybe? Soviet-era?
不一定 那玩意三百米长
Doubtful. That's 300 meters.
比我们那时候能建出来的东西大多了
Considerably larger than anything we know they built back then.
但是诡异的地方在这
But herds the spooky pan.
那东西周围覆盖的冰
The ice surrounding the object...
大概在上面有两万年了
...it's nearly twenty thousand years old.
莲恩小姐
Miss Lane?
别乱走 这里到了半夜
Try not to wander.
温度会降到零下40度
Temperatures drop to minus 40 at night around here.
春天过完了才能找到你的尸体
Wouldn't find your body till after spring.
那就这样吧
And there you go.
我想解手怎么办？
What if I need to tinkle?
角落里有个桶
There's a bucket in the corner.
你到底要去哪儿？
Where the hell are you going?
你好？
Hello?
没事了 没事了 没事了 没事的
It's all right, it's all right, it's all right. It's all right.
你内出血了
You're hemorrhaging internally...
要是现在我不止血
...and if I don't cauterize this bleed...
怎么能…？
How can...?
我有常人没有的能力
I can do things that other people can't.
抓住我的手
Now hold my hand.
会疼的
This is gonna hurt.
哈迪上校和他的团队
What Colonel Hardy and his team surmised...
猜测这会是一艘苏联时代的潜艇
...was a Soviet-era submarine...
它的真面目却更加奇特
...was actually something much more exotic.
周围冰孔的同位素分析表明...
An isotope analysis of the surrounding ice bores suggests that an object...
该物体已被困于冰川之中超过一万八千年
...had been trapped in the glacier for over 18,000 years.
而救我的人
As for my rescuer?
在该物体起飞的同时消失了
He disappeared during the object's departure...
背景调查发现 他的工作历史...
A background check revealed that his work history...
和身份均为伪造
...and identity had been falsified.
关于救我的人
The questions raised by my rescuer's...
存在与否的考量确实惊人
...existence are frightening to contemplate...
但我也知道自己所见属实
...but I also know what I saw.
因此我得出了一个必然的结论
"And I have arrived at the inescapable conclusion...
即该物体与它的乘坐者
...that the object and its occupant...
并非地球产物
...did not originate on Earth."
这样没法上报 里面可能有一半是你的幻觉
I can't print this, Lois. You might have hallucinated half of it.
可平民承包商证实了我的故事？
What about the contractors who corroborated my story?
五角大楼否认有船的存在
The Pentagon is denying that there was a ship.
他们当然否认 他们就该否认
Of course they are. They're supposed to.
因为他们是五角大楼
It's the Pentagon.
佩里 拜托 我们说的可是我
Perry,come on, it's me we're talking about.
- 我是一个普利策奖获奖记者   - 那就有点名记者样
- I'm a Pulitzer Prize-winning reporter.       - Then act like it.
- 不报出去我就辞职   - 走不了
- Print it or I walk.       - You can't.
你签了合同的
You're under contract.
我不会报道外星人隐藏于寻常人之中的故事
I'm not running a story about aliens walking among us.
绝对不会
Never gonna happen.
这位女士的苏格兰威士忌纯饮
That's a Scotch, straight-up, for the lady.
我现在就发原文给你
I'm sending you the article.
我的编辑不肯报 但如果碰巧在网上泄露了的话...
My editor won't print it, but if it leaked online...
懂了
Got it.
但你不是曾经把我的网站形容为...
But didn't you once describe my site...
满溢谎言的毒瘤吗？
...as a creeping cancer of falsehoods?
我还这么认为 但我想让这个故事见光
I stand by my words, Woodburn, but I want this story out there.
为什么？
Why?
因为我想让我的神秘男子知道我知道真相
Because I want my mystery man to know I know the truth.
递归诊断完成
Recursive diagnostics complete...
导示影像已授权
Guiding presence authenticated.
系统运转正常
All systems operational.
看见你在那里长大成人...
To see you standing there having grown into an adult...
要是莱拉能亲眼得见就好了
If only Lara could have witnessed this.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是你的父亲 卡尔
I am your father, Kal.
起码是他的身影
Or at least a shadow of him.
他的意识
His consciousness.
我叫乔•艾尔
My name was Jor-El.
那卡尔
And Kal?
是我的名字吗？
That's my name.
叫 卡尔•艾尔
Kal-El. It is.
我有好多问题
I have so many questions.
我从哪里来？
Where do I come from?
你为什么要送我来这里？
Why did you send me here?
你来自氪星
You came from Krypton.
一个比地球环境更恶劣的世界
A world with a much harsher environment than Earths.
很久以前
Long ago...
在大扩张的时代
...in an era of expansion...
我们的种族探索一颗颗星球
...our race spread out through the stars...
寻觅可以常驻的新世界
...seeking new worlds to settle upon.
这艘侦察船是射入虚空的数千艘之一
This scout ship was one of thousands launched into the void.
我们在其他行星上建造前哨
We built outposts on other planets...
用巨大的机器按我们的需求重塑环境
musing great machines to reshape environments to our needs.
十万年来我们的文明蓬勃发展
For 100,000 years, our civilization flourished...
创造了许多奇迹
...accomplishing wonders.
发生了什么？
What happened?
我们创造了人造人口控制系统
Artificial population control was established.
遗弃了太空探索的前哨
The outposts on space exploration were abandoned.
我们用尽了自然资源
We exhausted our natural resources.
因此我们行星的核心变得不稳定
As a result, our planet's core became unstable.
最终我们的军事领袖
Eventually, our military leader...
佐德将军企图发动政变
...General Zod, attempted a coup.
但为时已晚
But by then it was too late.
你妈妈和我预见了未来灾难
Your mother and I foresaw the coming calamity...
我们采取了某些措施以确保你的生存
...and we took certain steps to ensure your survival.
这是始源室
This is a genesis chamber.
所有氪星人都在这样的小房间里被孕育
All Kryptonians were conceived in chambers such as this.
每个出生的孩子都有一个预定的角色
Every child was designed to fulfill a pre-determined role in our society...
工人
...as a worker...
战士 领导者等等
...a warrior, a leader and so on.
你妈妈和我相信氪星失去了一些珍贵的东西
Your mother and I believed Krypton lost something precious.
选择和机会的要素
The element of choice, of chance.
要是一个孩子的梦想是...
What if a child dreamed of becoming something...
成为预定较色以外的角色呢？
mother than what society had intended for him or her?
要是他渴望更伟大的东西呢？
What if a child aspired to something greater?
你就是这种信念的体现 卡尔
You were the embodiment of that belief, Kal.
几世纪以来氪星的第一个自然分娩的孩子
Krypton's first natural birth in centuries.
所以我们才冒如此大的风险救你
That's why we risked so much to save you.
你们为什么不跟我一起来呢？
Why didn't you come with me?
我们做不到 卡尔
We couldn't, Kal.
不论我们多么渴望
No matter how much we wanted to.
不论我们有多爱你
No matter how much we loved you.
你母亲莱拉和我 都跟佐德一样
Your mother, Lara, and I...
是我们世界生产出来的失败产物
...were a product of the failures of our world as much as Zod was...
我们与它的命运紧紧相连
...tied to its fate.
- 那我是孤单一人了   - 不
- So I'm alone.       - No.
你既是氪星的子嗣 也是地球的孩子
You're as much a child of Earth now as you are of Krypton.
你能体现两个世界的精华
You can embody the best of both worlds.
你母亲和我致力保护的梦想
A dream your mother and I dedicated our lives to preserve.
地球人与我们不同 这不假
The people of Earth are different from us, it's true.
但最终我相信这是件好事
But, ultimately, I believe that's a good thing.
他们不一定会犯与我们相同的错误
They won't necessarily make the same mistakes we did.
只要有你的引导 卡尔
Not if you guide them, Kal.
只要你带给他们希望
Not if you give them hope.
这个符号就是这个意思
That's what this symbol means.
艾尔家族的标志代表希望
The symbol of the house of El means hope.
那种希望的体现在于...
Embodied within that hope is the fundamental belief...
让每个人的潜力成为善的力量
...in the potential of every person to be a force for good.
你可以将这一点带给他们
That's what you can bring them.
为什么我这么与众不同？
Why am I so different from them?
地球的太阳比氪星的太阳更年轻更明亮
Earth's sun is younger and brighter than Krypton's was.
你的细胞汲取了它的辐射
Your cells have drunken its radiation...
加强你的肌肉 皮肤以及感官
...strengthening your muscles, your skin, your senses.
地球的引力较弱 但大气更加滋润
Earth's gravity is weaker, yet its atmosphere is more nourishing.
你在这里变得会比我想象中的更强
You've grown stronger here than I ever could have imagined.
知道多强的唯一办法就是
The only way to know how strong...
不断测试你的极限
...is to keep testing your limits.
你会带给地球人为之奋斗的理想
You will give the people of Earth an ideal lo strive towards.
他们会在你身后努力追赶
They'll race behind you.
他们会失足
They will stumble.
会倒下
They will fall.
但最后
But In time...
他们会在太阳下与你比肩 卡尔
...they will join you in the sun, Kal.
到最后
In time...
你会帮助他们创造奇迹
you will help them accomplish wonders.
先从追踪有他出现的都市传说开始
You start with the urban legends...
- 他醒来后都涌现了出来   - 这是乔
- ...that have sprung up in his wake.        - That's Joe.
所有声称见过他的朋友的朋友
The friends of a friend who have seen him.
他过去在这里工作
He worked here.
对某些人而言 他是守护天使
For some he was a guardian angel.
对其他人来讲 他是个谜 是个格格不入的幽灵
For others, a cipher, a ghost who never quite fit in...
好吧 我是说我们在靠近石油钻机
Well, I was saying we were coming towards the oil rig.
随着你排除困难追溯过去 故事开始渐渐成型
As you work your way back in time, the stories form a pattern.
我在找皮特•罗斯 你认识他吗？
I'm looking for a Pete Ross. Do you know him?
是皮特•罗斯吗？
Pete Ross?
我想跟您谈谈你年轻时候的一场事故
I'd like to talk to you about an accident when you were younger.
一辆冲进河里的校车
A school bus that went into the river.
杰斯
Dusty.
肯特夫人吗？
Mrs. Kent?
我是露易丝•莲恩 来自《星球日报》
I'm Lois Lane. I'm from the  Daily Planet.
安静
Quiet.
我来自《星球日报》 我想跟您谈谈你的儿子
I'm from the Daily Planet and I'd like to talk to you about your son.
我早就知道要是我查得够仔细 你最后会找到我
I figured if I turned over enough stones you'd eventually find me.
你从哪来？在这里做什么？
Where are you from? What are you doing here?
让我讲你的故事
Let me tell your story.
要是我不想让我的故事被讲出去呢？
What if I don't want my story told?
最后它总会被传出去的
It's going to come out eventually.
有人会拿到相片或是查到你的住处
Somebody's going to get a photograph or figure out where you live.
- 那我就再次消失   - 唯一的办法就是
- Then I'll disappear again.       - The only way you could disappear...
不再帮助人们 我感觉你不会那样的
...is to stop helping people altogether, and I sense that's not an option for you.
我父亲相信要是世界查出我的真实身份
My father believed that if the world found out who I really was...
他们会拒绝我
...they'd reject me...
因为恐惧
...out of fear.
我厌倦了安全
I'm tired of safe.
我只想有生之年做些有用的事
I just wanna do something useful with my life.
那么开农场 养活大家 就没有用吗？
So farming, feeding people. That's not useful?
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
我们的家族整整五代都以农场为生 克拉克
Our family's been farming for five generations.
你的家族 不是我的
Your family, not mine.
我都不知道自己为什么要听你说 你不是我爸爸
I don't even know why I'm listening to you. You're not my dad.
你只是某个在地里捡到我的人
You're just some guy who found me in a field.
克拉克
Clark.
没关系 玛莎
It's all right, Martha.
他说得对 克拉克说得有道理
He's right. Clark has a point.
我们不是你的父母
We're not your parents.
但我们力求做到最好
But we've been doing the best we can.
我们也在尽可能地改进 也许...
And we've been making this up as we go along, so maybe...
我们所谓的最好已经不够好了
Maybe our best isn't good enough anymore.
听着 爸
Look, Dad...
等一下
Hold on.
快去天桥躲着
Go for the overpass.
快点去躲起来
Go for the overpass!
找掩护 快找掩护
Take cover! Take cover!
- 在那边 跟上他们   - 找掩护
- Over there. Just follow them.       - Take cover.
她被困住了
She's stuck.
汉克在车里
Hank's still in the car.
Hank's in the car.
- 我去救它 我去救   - 不
- I'll get him, I'll get him.       - No, no.
带你妈去天桥
Get your mom to the overpass.
汉克 快来
Hank! Hank! Come!
- 乔纳森   - 妈 待在这
- Jonathan!       - Mom, stay here.
爸
Dad!
因为我的信任 父亲去世了
I let my father die because I trusted him.
因为他相信世界还没有准备好
Because he was convinced that I had to wait.
我必须等待下去
That the world was not ready.
你怎么想？
What do you think?
你得小心了 露易丝
You better watch out, Lois.
佩里要冲你发火了
Hey, Perry's gunning for you.
他知道你是伍德伯恩的匿名信息源
He knows you're Woodburn's anonymous source
都等不及好好教训你了
and cannot wait to rip you a new one.
看看她 哈哈
Oh, look at her. Ha, ha, ha.
我告诉过你不要跟这条线 然后呢？
I told you not to run with this, and what do you do?
你却让伍德伯恩将之传遍了网络
You let Woodburn just shotgun it all over the Internet.
现在出版商想让我起诉你
Now the publishers want me to sue you.
好吧 如果还有用的话 我放弃
Well, if it makes a difference, I'm dropping it.
就那样吗？
Whoa, just like that?
没错
Yep.
你的线索怎么了？
What happened to your leads?
没什么意思 整个故事都是过眼云烟
They didn't pan out. The story is smoke.
也有可能没引起你期盼的公众注意罢了
Or it didn't get the traction you hoped?
两周的无薪休假
Two weeks leave...
算是惩罚你了
...no pay, that's your penance.
你再这么弄一次
You try something like this again...
- 我就开除你   - 好吧
- ...you're done here.       - Fine.
你这么迫不及待地附和我
Let's make it three weeks
改成三周休假比较合适
since you're so willing to agree.
露易丝 我绝不认为
I believe you saw something, Lois.
你的线索毫无价值
But not for a moment do I believe that your leads just went cold.
因此不管你放弃的理由是什么
So whatever your reasons are for dropping it...
我相信你做得没错
...I think you're doing the right thing.
为什么？
Why?
如果人们得知地球有这样的人的存在
Can you imagine how people on this planet would react...
你能想象人们会有何种反应吗？
...if they knew there was someone like this out there?
去接接他
Go get him.
看看我儿子
Well, look at you.
一个记者来过
A reporter came by here.
是个朋友 别担心
She's a friend. Don't worry.
妈妈
Mom.
怎么了？
What?
- 我找到了   - 谁？
- I found them.       - Who?
我的父母
My parents.
我的族人
My People.
我现在知道自己的身世了
I know where I come from now.
哇
Wow.
那真是太好了
That's wonderful.
太为你高兴了 克拉克
I'm so happy for you, Clark.
- 怎么了？ - 没事
- What?       - It's nothing.
你尚在襁褓中时 我整夜在婴儿床边陪你
When you were a baby I used to lay by your crib at night...
听着你的呼吸
...listening to you breathe.
那对你来说不容易
It was hard for you.
你努力着
You struggled.
我无时不刻不担心你
And I worried all the time.
你怕真相暴露吗？
You worried the truth would come out.
不
No.
你的真相吗？那就是你太可爱了
The truth about you is beautiful.
第一眼见到你的时候我们就知道
We saw that the moment we laid eyes on you.
知道有一天 世人也终归会发现
We knew that one day, the whole world would see that.
我只是...
I'm just...
担心他们会让我们分离
I'm worried they'll take you away from me.
我哪也不去 妈妈
I'm not going anywhere, Mom.
我保证
I promise.
斯旺威克将军 长官
General Swanwick, sir.
这是什么 博士？彗星还是小行星？
What am I looking at, doc? Comet? Asteroid?
彗星可不会修正航道 将军
Comets don't make course corrections, general.
在某个天文爱好者看到并引起恐慌前 我想让你好好看一下
Wanted you to see this before some amateur with a telescope creates a worldwide panic.
这艘船似乎
The ship appears to have...
将自己送入了月球同步轨道
...inserted itself into a lunar synchronous orbit...
我不知道为什么
...though I have no idea why.
你有试过和它取得联系吗？
Have you tried... communicating with it?
他们至今没有回应
Well, they haven't responded as of yet.
我个人的猜测是 不管是谁在操纵飞船...
I'm just speculating, but I think whoever's at the helm of that thing...
他一定想来个惊人的着陆
...is looking to make a dramatic entrance.
有人知道墨盒放在哪了吗？
Anybody know where we keep the toner?
- 怎么了？ - 新闻都在报道
- What's going on?       - It's all over the news.
你得来看看
You gotta see this.
克拉克
Clark.
嗯？
Yeah?
来了
Coming.
这是个突发新闻 身份不明
This is a breaking news. An unidentified...
你并不是一个人
You are not alone.
你 并不是 一个人
RSS也有这信息
It's coming in on the RSS feeds.
你并不是一个人
You are not alone.
手机上也有
It's on my phone too.
我是佐德将军
My name is General Zod.
我来自一个遥远的星球
I come from a world far from yours.
我穿越了茫茫星海来找你们
I have journeyed across an ocean of stars to reach you.
你们庇护了我的一个子民
For some time, your world has sheltered one of my citizens.
现在我要求你们把他交出来
I request that you return this individual...
给我处理
...to my custody.
因为某些原因 他选择向你们隐瞒他的存在
For reasons unknown, he has chosen to keep his existence a secret from you.
他竭尽全力融入你们
He will have made efforts to blend in.
他看起来和你们相似
He will look like you.
但他不是同族
But he is not one of you.
如果有谁知道
To those of you who may know...
他的位置
...of his current location.
那你们星球的命运
...the fate of your planet...
就在你手中了
...rests in your hands.
卡尔•艾尔 听到了吗？
To Kai-El, I say this:
24小时内出来投降
Surrender within 24 hours...
或者让整个世界来承担后果
...or watch this world suffer the consequences...
我们对他一无所知 对吗？
We hardly know anything about him, isn't that right?
如果他真的不想害我们
If he truly means us no harm...
那他应该回归他的族人 去承担后果
...he'll turn himself in and face the consequences.
如果他不肯去
And if he won't do that...
也许我们该送他去
...then maybe we should.
《星球日报》的露易丝•莲恩知道他是谁
The Daily Planet's Lois Lane knows who this guy is. She's...
我认为她是我们该质问的人
...the one we should be questioning.
- 等等 你是说露易丝•莲恩   - 你好
- Hold on. You're saying Lois Lane...        - Hello?
你在看新闻吗？播了一早上了
Are you watching this crap? Been running all morning.
这次我竟然完全同意伍德伯恩的观点 你见过他吗？
For once I agree with Woodburn. Have you seen him?
- 知道他在哪吗？ - 不知道 即使知道 我也不会说
- Do you know where he is?        - No. Even if I did, I wouldn't say.
整个世界岌岌可危
The entire world is being threatened here.
这可不是你展现新闻道德的时候
This is not time for you to fall back on journalistic integrity.
事态严重了 露易丝
This is serious, Lois.
FBI都来了 他们在说叛国罪什么的
The FBI is here. They're throwing around words like "treason."
我得走了
I gotta go.
FBI 举起手来
FBI. Hands up.
扔了袋子 马上
Drop the bag. Now.
据我采访的政府官员说
Regarding the visitors themselves we know...
现在我们所知甚少
...very little. According to government officials...
尽管他们的语调并不友善
...the visitors do not represent a threat...
但来客并不代表着威胁
...despite the ominous tone of their message.
当然了 大家心中都有一个疑问
Then of course there's the question on everyone's mind:
这个卡尔•艾尔是谁？他真的存在吗？
"Who is this Kai-El person? Does he actually exist?"
他如何在我们之中隐藏了这么久？
"How could he have remained hidden from us for so long?"
来啊 肯特
Come on, Kent.
来啊 打回来啊
Come on. Fight back.
站起来 肯特
Get up, Kent.
就这点水平
So is that it?
你就这点实力吗？
Is that all you've got?
来啊 肯特
Come on, Kent.
过来
Come on!
他们伤到你了吗？
Did they hurl you?
你知道那不可能
You know they can't.
我不是那个意思 我是说 你还好吗？
That's not what I meant. I meant, are you all right?
我想痛扁那个屁孩 我想狠狠地揍他
I wanted to hit that kid. I wanted to hit him bad.
我知道你想
I know you did. I mean...
我甚至也想让你揍他 可是然后呢？
...part of me even wanted you to, but then what?
你就会高兴了吗？
Make you feel any better?
你只需要决定你想成长为什么样的人 克拉克
You just have to decide what kind of man you want to grow up to be, Clark.
因为无论成为什么样 好人或是坏人 你都会...
Because whoever that man is, good character or bad, he's...
改变这个世界
He's gonna change the world.
你脑中所虑为何事？
What's on your mind?
我不知从何说起
I don't know where to start.
悉听尊便
Wherever you want.
昨晚出现的飞船
That ship that appeared last night.
我就是他们要找的人
I'm the one they're looking for.
你知道
Do you know...
他们找你的原因吗？
...why they want you?
不 但这个佐德将军
No. But this General Zod...
即使我投降 他也未必会信守诺言
...even if I surrender, there's no guarantee he'll keep his word, but...
但若我投降就可以拯救地球的话
...if there's a chance I can save Earth by turning myself in...
难道我不该这么做吗？
...shouldn't I take it?
你的直觉呢？
What does your gut tell you?
佐德不可信
Zod can't be trusted.
问题是
The problem is...
我也不知道地球的人民可不可信
...I'm not sure the people of Earth can be either.
有时候你必须坚信不疑
Sometimes you have to take a leap of faith first.
信任会随之而来
The trust part comes later.
好了 我们注意到你了
All right. You've got our attention.
你想怎么样？
What is it you want?
我要和露易丝•莲恩谈话
I would like to speak to Lois Lane.
你凭什么认为她在这里？
What makes you think she's here?
别浪费时间 将军
Don't play games with me, general.
只要你们能保证露易丝的自由 我就投降
I'll surrender, but only if you guarantee Lois's freedom.
你为什么向佐德投降？
Why are you surrendering to Zod?
我是向人类屈服 这并不一样
I'm surrendering to mankind. There's a difference.
你让他们把你铐起来了吗？
You let them handcuff you?
我要是抵抗 就不算是投降了
Wouldn't be much of a surrender if I resisted.
如果他们这样做感到安全
And if it makes them feel more secure...
那么 如他们所愿吧
...then all the better for it.
S这个字母有含义吗？
What's the S stand for?
那不是S
It's not an S.
在我的星球 那代表希望
On my world it means hope.
好吧 在地球这就是个S
Well, here, it's an S.
我想想
How about...
先生
Sir?
- 嗨 我是…博士   - 埃米尔•汉密尔顿
- Hi, my name is Dr. E...       - Emil Hamilton.
我知道 我可以看到你上衣口袋里的身份卡
I know, I can see your ID tag in your breast pocket.
还有一袋吃了一半的糖
Along with a half-eaten roll of Lifesavers.
我也能看到隔壁房间的一队士兵
I can also see the soldiers in the next room...
还有你的镇压用特工
...preparing that tranquilizing agent of yours.
没必要的
You won't need it.
先生 我们不可能毫无准备
Sir, you can't expect us to not take precautions.
你很可能携带了外星病原体
You could be carrying some kind of alien pathogen.
我已经在这里生活了33年了 博士
Been here for 33 years, doctor.
- 还没感染任何人   - 一面之辞而已
- Haven't infected anyone yet.       - That you know of.
我们有安全方面的考虑
We have legitimate security concerns.
既然你向莲恩小姐透露了身份
You revealed your identity to Miss Lane over there.
为什么没告诉我们？
Why won't you do the same with us?
我们把话说开了吧 将军
Let's put our cards on the table here, general.
你们怕我是因为你们无法控制我
You're scared because you can't control me.
现在不能 以后也不能
You don't, and you never will.
但那并不意味着我是敌人
But that doesn't' mean I'm your enemy.
那谁是敌人？
Then who is?
佐德吗？
Zod?
我正是担心这一点
That's what I'm worried about.
就算是这样
Be that as it may...
我也收到了命令要把你交给他
...I've been given orders to hand you over to him.
做你必须做的吧 将军
Do what you have to do, general.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢什么？
For what?
谢谢你信任我
For believing in me.
到最后也没改变什么
Didn't make much difference in the end.
改变了我
It did to me.
他们来了
They're coming.
你该走了
You should leave now.
快走 露易丝
Go, Lois.
卡尔•艾尔
Kal-El.
我是副指挥官芙拉•奥
I'm sub-commander Faora-UI.
代表佐德将军 向你问候
On behalf of General Zod, I extend you his greetings.
- 你是指挥官吗？ - 我是
- Are you the ranking officer here?       - I am.
佐德将军希望这个女人陪我走
General Zod would like this woman to accompany me.
你要的只是你的族人
You asked for the alien.
你并没有说要带走我们的人
You didn't say anything about one of our own.
需要我告诉将军你不答应吗？
Shall I tell the general you're unwilling to comply?
我不在乎你怎么告诉他
I don't care what you tell him.
没关系
It's all right.
我去
I'll go.
人类无法适应我们飞船中的大气成分
The atmospheric composition on our ship is not compatible with humans.
过去以后 你必须带上呼吸器
You need to wear a breather...
不要靠近
...beyond this point.
卡尔•艾尔
Kal-El.
你都不知道
You have no idea how long...
我们找了你多久
...we've been searching for you.
我想你就是佐德
I take it you're Zod?
是佐德将军
General Zod.
- 我们的统领   - 没关系 芙拉•奥
- Our commander.       - It's all right, Faora.
原谅卡尔的无礼
We can forgive Kal any lapses in decorum.
他还不熟悉我们的礼仪
He's a stranger to our ways.
我们应该好好庆祝一下 而不该争吵
This should be cause for celebration, not conflict.
别冲突
Not conflict.
我...
I...
感觉不舒服
...feel strange.
很虚弱
Weak.
他怎么了？
What's happening to him?
他的身体对船上的大气有排斥
He's rejecting our ship's atmospherics.
克拉克
Clark.
你用了一辈子来适应地球的环境
You've spent a lifetime adapting to Earth's ecology...
却适应不了我们自己的
...but never adapted to ours.
快帮帮他
Help him.
克拉克
Clark.
帮帮他
Help him.
快帮帮他
你好 卡尔
Hello, Kal.
还是你更喜欢我叫你克拉克
Or do you prefer Clark?
那是他们给你起的名字
That's the name they gave you.
不是吗？
Isn't it?
我曾是氪星的军事统领
I was Krypton's military leader...
而你父亲是我们的首席科学家
...your father our foremost scientist.
我们唯一达成共识的一点就是
The only thing we agreed on...
氪星就要毁灭了
...was that Krypton was dying.
我拼命保护我们的文化
In return for my efforts to protect our civilization...
保卫我们的星球
...and save our planet...
得到的回报却是我们都被放逐到幽灵区
...I and my fellow officers were sentenced to the Phantom Zone.
而我们星球的毁灭却让我们重获自由
And then the destruction of our world freed us.
我们四处漂泊
We were adrift,
注定漂流在我们星球的残骸之中
destined to float amongst the ruins of our planet...
直至死亡
...until we starved.
你们是怎么找到地球来的？
How did you find your way to Earth?
我们把幽灵推进器改造成了高速飞行器
We managed to retrofit the phantom projector into a hyperdrive.
你父亲也是对飞船做了类似的修改 把你送到了这里
Your father made a similar modification to the craft that brought you here.
所以囚禁我们的工具
And so the instrument of our damnation...
同时也拯救了我们
...became our salvation.
我们找遍了旧殖民地的前哨站
We sought out the old colonial outposts...
想要寻找生命的迹象
...looking for signs of life.
但找到的只有死亡
But all we found was death.
这些前哨站早和氪星失去联络
Cut off from Krypton, these outposts...
以后就废弃了
...withered and died long ago.
我们把能用的都带走了
We salvaged what we could...
盔甲 武器
...armor, weapons...
还有一个世界引擎
...even a world engine.
我们准备了33年
For 33 years we prepared...
直到我们侦测到一个求救信号
...until finally we detected a distress beacon...
是你在老侦察机里发出的
...which you triggered when you accessed the ancient scout ship.
是你把我们带到这里的 卡尔
You led us here, Kal.
现在你有能力拯救我们的种族
Now it's within your power to save what remains of your race.
在氪星上
On Krypton...
所有未出生孩子的遗传基因
...the genetic template for every being yet to be born...
都被编写在公民档案里
...is encoded in the registry of citizens.
你父亲偷走了档案的密典
Your father stole the registry's Codex...
藏在了带你来的太空舱里
...and stored it in the capsule that brought you here.
为什么呢？
For what purpose?
这样氪星就能在地球上重生
So that Krypton can live again on Earth.
密典在哪里 卡尔？
Where is the Codex, Kal?
如果氪星重生
If Krypton lives again...
地球会怎么样？
...what happens to Earth?
重生总需要建立在毁灭之上
The foundation has to be built on something.
连你父亲都知道这一点
Even your father recognized that.
不 佐德
No, Zod.
我不会帮你的
I can't be a part of this.
那么你会帮谁呢？
Then what can you be a part of?
不
No!
佐德
Zod!
不
No!
你的父亲为荣誉献出了自己
Your father acquitted himself with honor, Kal.
是你杀了他？
You killed him?
是的
I did.
我永远都摆脱不了这件事的阴影
And not a day goes by where it doesn't haunt me.
但如果重来一次 我还是会这么做
But if I had to do it again, I would.
我要对我的人民负责
I have a duty to my people...
我不会让任何人阻止我
...and I will not allow anyone to prevent me from carrying it out.
那是什么 少校？
What's the sit-rep, major?
侦测到两架敌机从外星飞船中发射
DSP pinged two bogeys launching from the alien ship.
- 荧幕显示   - 好的 长官
- Put it up.       - Yes, sir.
就是这个
There it is.
接无线电4号
Re-task IKon-4...
-  再拉近点   - 好的
- ...and get me a closer look.       - Yes, sir.
指挥部
Command, the word...
今天的暗号是三叉戟
...of the day is trident.
有两架外星飞船正在接近
We have two alien craft on aggressive approach.
无线电4号已接通
Ikon-4 coming online.
速度有多快？
Air speed?
380海里 正在进入堪萨斯州上空
380 knots, entering Kansas...
他们不回应我们
...airspace. Not responding to our hails.
你不要浪费体力了
You're wasting your efforts.
你从地球的太阳得到的力量
The strength you derived from the Earth's sun...
在我们的船上完全没有用
...has been neutralized aboard our ship.
在这里
Here...
这样的环境下
...in this environment...
你就跟人类一样脆弱
...you are as weak as a human.
你从哪冒出来的？
Where did you come from?
主控钥匙里 莲恩小姐
The command key, Miss Lane.
多亏了你 我正在被上传到这艘船的主程序里
Thanks to you, I'm uploading to the ship's mainframe.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是卡尔的父亲
I am Kai's father.
你能帮我们吗？
Can you help us?
这艘船是我设计的
I designed this ship.
我能改造它的大气结构
I can modify its atmospheric composition...
使人类适应
...to human compatibility.
我们能阻止他们
We can stop them.
我们能把他们送回幽灵区
We can send them back to the Phantom Zone.
怎么做？
How?
我来教你
I can teach you.
然后你再教给卡尔
And in turn, you can teach Kal.
你会帮我吗？
Will you help me?
船上的警报响了
The ship's crew are alerted.
我们得快点
We need to move quickly.
把主控钥匙拿上
Retrieve the command key.
- 是你做的吗？ - 是的 把她的武器拿上
- Did you do that?       - Yes. Pick up her sidearm.
发生了什么？
What's happening?
右边
To your right.
开火
Fire.
后面
Behind you.
安全待在救生舱里
Secure yourself inside the open pod.
旅途平安 莲恩小姐
Safe travels, Miss Lane. It's unlikely...
我们应该不可能再见面了
...we'll see each other again.
记住 幽灵引擎是阻止他们的关键
Remember, the phantom drives are essential in stopping them.
把头偏向左边
Move your head to the left.
佐德说的关于密典的事是真的吗？
Is it true what Zod said about the Codex?
把船壁打破
Strike that panel.
我们想要你学习人类最重要的是什么
We wanted you to learn what it meant to be human first...
所以如果有一天 时机成熟
...so that one day, when the time was right,
你会成为两个种族沟通的桥梁
you could be the bridge between two peoples.
看
Look.
露易丝
Lois.
你能救她 卡尔
You can save her, Kal.
你能拯救所有人
You can save all of them.
你安全了
You'll be safe here.
- 你没事吧？ - 没事
- Are you all right?       - Yeah.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我不是故意告诉他们你的事 他们对我动了手脚
I didn't wanna tell them anything, but they did something to me.
- 他们看穿了我的心思   - 没关系 露易丝
- They looked inside my mind...       - It's okay, Lois.
他们也对我做了同样的事
They did the same thing to me.
克拉克
Clark!
带他来的那艘船
The craft he arrived in...
它在哪里？
...where is it?
去死吧
Go to hell.
在那边
There.
密典不在这里
The Codex is not here.
他藏在哪了？
Where has he hidden it?
我不知道
I don't know.
密典在哪里？
Where is the Codex?!
你居然敢威胁我妈妈
You think you can threaten my mother?!
你对我做了什么？
What have you done to me?
我父母教我要磨练我的感官 佐德
My parents taught me to hone my senses, Zod.
专注
Focus...
在自己想看的东西上
...on just what I wanted to see.
你没了头盔
Without your helmet...
可以感受到更多东西
...you're getting everything.
很难受
And it hurts...
是吧？
...doesn't it?
别站在窗户边上
Get away from the window.
都进去 这里不安全
Get inside. It's not safe.
全体听命 这里是守护者 我是空中指挥官
All players, this is Guardian. I am airborne mission commander.
我已经事先接触过并观察过
I have previously encountered and observed...
我们将要接近的目标
...the beings we're about to engage.
他们非常危险 我们可以...
They are extremely dangerous and we have been authorized...
使用致命武器
...to use deadly force.
收到 守护者 我们正接近目标
Roger, Guardian, we are inbound to target.
开火
Cleared hot. Weapons free.
11号 开火
Copy, 11. Weapons free.
这里是雷电11号
Thunder 11...
锁定三个目标
...tally three targets.
雷电11号
Thunder 11...
干得漂亮 请求立即再次攻击
...good hit. Request immediate re-attack.
收到 守护者 准备二次攻击
Roger, Guardian. We'll make a second gun run...
航向212度
...on a heading of 212 degrees.
雷电11号 快弹出逃生
Thunder 11, eject!
快弹出逃生
Eject!
雷电11号 快弹出逃生
Thunder 11, eject!
有敌人向我冲来
I have a bogey incoming!
该死
Oh, shit.
你太弱了
You are weak...
艾尔之子
...son of El.
对自己没信心
Unsure of yourself.
我们并不像你
The fact that you possess a sense of morality...
受道德准则的束缚
...and we do not...
而这正是我们进化的优势
...gives us an evolutionary advantage.
如果说历史证明了什么
And if history has proven anything...
那就是进化者永远更强大
...it is that evolution always wins.
我们来了
CCT, we're approaching...
着陆 全力下降
...LZ Jayhawk. Get down in five.
走吧 前进
Let's go. Go to the LZ.
收到 中士 出发
Roger, sarge. let's go!
公牛流浪者号
All rangers, I need you...
瞄准所有目标
...to engage the targets.
守护者 这里是一号战场
Guardian, this is Badger 01.
那个穿蓝衣服的家伙怎么办？
What about the guy in blue?
我说了
I said engage...
攻击所有目标
...all targets.
战斗 战斗
Contact. Contact.
你没事吧？
You okay?
我们被击中了
We're auto-rotating, going in hard.
我们受到了撞击
Brace for impact.
我们受撞击
正在坠落
We're going in hard!
守护者已坠毁 重复一次 守护者已坠毁
Fallen angel. Fallen angel. Guardian is down. I repeat, Guardian is down.
守护者 听到请回答
Guardian, do you read?
雷电12号呼叫守护者
Thunder 12, calling Guardian.
- 能收到吗？ - 雷电12号
- Do you read?        - Thunder 12...
这里是守护者
...this is Guardian.
火力全部对准这里 不用管我们
Put down everything you've got north of my position.
- 这里是危险区域   - 收到 危险区域
- This will be danger-close.        - Copy, danger-close.
祝你好运 长官
Good luck, sir.
死得光荣就是死得其所
A good death is its own reward.
你赢不了的
You will not win.
你每救一个人
For every human you save...
我们会多杀一百万
...we will kill a million more. Unh!
还有敌人吗？还有敌人吗？
Do we have an all clear? Do we have an all clear?
A小队
Alpha team, sit-rep. Alpha team.
收到请回答
Do you copy? Alpha team.
这个人不是我们的敌人
This man is not our enemy.
谢谢你 上校
Thank you, colonel.
妈妈
Mom?
我没事
I'm all right.
衣服很漂亮 儿子
Nice suit, son.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
这些只是身外之物 克拉克
It's only stuff, Clark.
总是会被取代的
It can always be replaced.
但你不能被取代
But you can't be.
妈妈 佐德说他要找的密典
Mom, Zod said this Codex...
可以让我的种族重生
...he's looking for can bring my people back.
这不是很好吗？
Isn't that a good thing?
我不认为他们想要分享这个世界
I don't think they're interested in sharing this world.
克拉克
Clark.
我知道怎么阻止他们
I know how to stop them.
发生了什么？
What happened down there?
他发现了我们一个暂时的弱点
He exposed a temporary weakness.
这已经不重要了
It is of little consequence...
因为我知道密典在哪儿了
...because I have located the Codex.
根本就不在太空舱里
It was never in the capsule.
乔•艾尔拿走了
Jor-el took the Codex...
记录着数十亿人基因的密典
...the DNA of a billion people, then he bonded it...
把它藏在他儿子的每一个细胞当中
...within his son's individual cells.
所有氪星人的后代
All of Krypton's heirs...
就藏在一个外星难民的身体里
...living hidden in one refugee's body.
要从卡尔•艾尔的细胞里拿到密典
Does Kal-El need to be alive...
需要他活着吗？
...for us to extract the Codex from his cells?
不用
No.
启动世界引擎
Release the world engine.
发生了什么？
What just happened?
那艘船一分为二
The ship just split in two.
一艘往东飞去了 另一艘向南半球去了
Track one is heading east, track two to the southern hemisphere.
- 速度有多快？ - 接近...
- How fast is that bogey moving?       - Approaching...
24马赫 并且还在加速
...Mach 24 and accelerating.
看起来像是要降落在南印度洋的某个地方
It's gonna impact somewhere in the Indian Ocean.
另一艘船也在降落
The rest of the ship is descending.
荧幕显示
Put it on the board now.
遵命
Yes, sir.
天啊
Oh, my God.
让幽灵引擎待命
Bring the phantom drive online.
已经与世界引擎建立连接
We are now slave to the world engine.
启动
Initiate.
他们发射过来的是什么？
What have they hit us with?
看上去像是某种重力武器
Looks like some kind of gravity...
和他们的飞船同步工作
...weapon. It's working in tandem with their ship.
一种可以增加地球质量的东西
Somehow they're increasing the Earth's mass...
利用微尘污浊大气
...clouding the atmosphere with particulates.
天哪
Oh, my God.
他们在进行环境改造
They're terraforming.
那是什么？
What's that?
行星工程
Planetary engineering...
修改地球上的大气和地形
...modifying the Earth's atmosphere and topography.
他们要把地球转化成氪星
Turning Earth into Krypton.
- 但是我们会怎么样？ - 理论上说...
- But what happens to us?       - Based on these readings...
- 不再有"我们"了    - 斯旺威克将军
- ...there won't be an "us."       - General Swanwick, sir.
控制塔来电
I'm on with the control tower.
哈迪上校正在路上 和他在一起的还有超人
Colonel Hardy's on his way and he's got Superman in tow.
超人？
Superman?
那个外星人 先生
The alien, sir.
他们叫他超人
That's what they're calling him. Superman.
我们有个计划 将军
We have a plan, general.
和我想的一样吗？
Is that what I think it is?
这是他坐的飞船
It's the ship he arrived in.
这艘飞船由某种叫幽灵引擎的物质驱动
This ship is powered by something called a phantom drive.
它能够扭曲时空
It bends space.
佐德的飞船运用了同样的原理 如果我们能让两者对撞
Zod's ship uses the same technology, and if we can make the two drives collide...
就能创造出一个奇异点
A singularity can be created.
- 就像黑洞   - 对
- Like a black hole.       - Yes.
所以如果我们打开通道
So if we open up this doorway...
理论上来说他们就应该被吸进去
...they should be pulled back in.
所以你想我们用那个炸掉他们
So you want us to bomb them with that?
将军 如果太空船达到
General, that craft maxes out...
17000磅 可以从C-17投掷下来
...17,000 pounds, we can drop it from a C-17.
这是可行的
It's a viable plan.
如果我不阻止印度洋上的机器
If I don't stop that machine over the Indian Ocean...
重力场还会继续扩大
...the gravity field will continue to expand.
如果那个东西是使地球氪星化
If that thing is making Earth more like Krypton...
你在它附近不会更脆弱吗？
...won't you be weaker around it?
有可能
Maybe.
但我不会让它阻止我试一试
I'm not about to let that stop me from trying.
你可能想后退一点
You might want to step back a little bit.
可能要再退一点
Maybe a little bit more.
芙拉
Faora.
你来指挥
Take command.
- 遵命   - 我要保证始源室的安全
- Yes, sir.       - I need to secure the genesis chamber...
还要向一个老朋友致意
...and pay my respects to an old friend.
守护者前往大都会
Guardian en route to Metropolis...
携带包裹
...package in tow.
被告知了F-35战机入境的会合点
Be advised, F-35s inbound to rendezvous point.
你现在应该在视觉接触
You should have visual contact now.
主控钥匙识别正确 始源室待命 先生
Command key accepted. Genesis chamber coming online, sir.
住手 佐德
Stop this, Zod...
趁还有时间
...while there's still time.
还没放弃对我说教呢 是吧 哪怕是死了
Haven't given up lecturing me, have you, even in death?
我不会让你用密典做这些
I will not let you use the Codex like this.
你没权力阻止我
You don't have the power to stop me.
我插入的主控钥匙已经废除了你的权限
The command key I have entered is revoking your authority.
飞船在我掌控之下了
This ship is now under my control.
北方司令部 这里是闪电1号
Northcom, Lightning 1, request...
请求释放导弹
...permission to unleash the hounds.
周围安全 可以袭击 可能的话发生作战损坏评估
Lightning 1, you are clear to engage. Send battle damage assessment when able. Out.
电子设备陷入混乱
Avionics are going haywire. The gravity field...
重力场牵引我们的导弹下坠 我们需要更加接近目标
...is pulling our missiles down. We gotta get closer.
好了各位
All right, everybody...
我们离开了 现在就离开大楼
...we're leaving. We're leaving the building now.
我失去了我的僚机驾驶员
I just lost my wingman.
飞机失控 飞机失控 飞机失控
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
各位 这边
Everybody, this way! Come on!
各位 快点 快 快
Everybody, come on! Keep moving, keep moving.
詹妮
Jenny!
天哪
Oh, my God.
玛丽
Perry!
走这边 快
Go! There! Go!
我们可以共存
Our people can co-exist.
这样我们就像你儿子那样
So we can suffer through years of pain
撑过数年的伤痛来适应环境？
trying to adapt like your son has?
- 你说的是种族屠杀   - 是的
- You're talking about genocide.       - Yes.
而且我正和一个鬼魂争论其功过
And I'm arguing its merits with a ghost.
我们都是鬼魂 佐德
We're both ghosts, Zod.
你不明白吗？你不愿放弃的氪星已经没了
Can't you see that? The Krypton you're clinging onto is gone.
你检查好入侵的情报了吗？
Ship, have you managed to quarantine this invasive intelligence?
- 失败了   - 好了
- You'll fail.        - I have.
准备好终结这一切
Then prepare to terminate it.
我不想争吵了 让我闭嘴
I'm tired of this debate. Silencing me...
改变不了任何事
...won't change anything.
我儿子...
My son...
比你强两倍
...is twice the man you were.
他会结束我们发起的种种
And he will finish what we started.
我保证
I can promise you that.
告诉我
Tell me...
你有乔•艾尔的记忆和良知
...you have Jor-El's memories, his conscience.
可你经历过他的痛苦吗？
Can you experience his pain?
我会从你儿子的尸体里提取密典
I will harvest the Codex from your son's corpse...
在他的尸骨之上重建氪星
...and I will rebuild Krypton atop his bones.
詹妮
Jenny.
- 詹妮 詹妮 你在哪？ - 我在这里
- Jenny. Jenny, where are you?       - I'm here!
- 这里 这里   - 詹妮
- I'm here. Here.       - Jenny.
撑住 撑住
Hold on, hold on.
我卡住了
I'm stuck.
- 我动不了 卡住了   - 好的
- I can't get free. I'm stuck.       - Okay.
我们会把你救出去 你别动
We'll get you out of there, all right? Just sit tight.
不不
No, no, no!
- 别离开我   - 我不会离开你
- Don't leave me.       - We're not gonna leave you.
- 好   - 伦巴第
- Okay.       - Lombard!
- 他妈的快过来帮忙   - 该死
- Get your ass over here and help me.       - Damn it.
- 用这个撬   - 给你
- We just gotta move this.       - Here.
用力试试看 好了吗？
Slide that in. You push, I'll pull, okay?
来吧
Go.
- 用力   - 天啊
- Push!       - Oh, my God.
越来越近了 用力
It's getting closer! Come on, push!
北方司令部 这里是守护者 可以投掷吗？
Northcom, this is Guardian. Are we cleared?
不行 守护者
Negative, Guardian.
快 用力啊
Come on! Push!
他做到了
He did it.
北方司令部 这里是守护者
Northcom, this is Guardian.
我们正经过调整线 一切良好
We're passing through phase line red. Good to go.
一路平安 守护者
Godspeed, Guardian.
整理包裹 准备投掷
Arm the package. You are cleared hot.
准备发出最后一击
We're lining up for the final run.
现在看你和汉密尔顿的了
It's up to you and Hamilton now.
搞什么
You gotta be kidding me.
理货员 包裹是否武装完毕？
Loadmaster, is the package ready to drop?
不行 守护者
Negative, Guardian.
出问题了 不该这样的
There's something wrong. It's not supposed to do this.
那应该怎样？
What's it supposed to do?
- 应该完全插进去   - 我看看
- It's supposed to go in all the way.       - Let me take a look.
副驾驶接管飞机
Co-pilot's aircraft.
我们已经排列好准备投掷了 还在等什么？
We are lined up for the drop. What's the hold up?
出现了点问题
We've had a setback.
瞄准飞机
Target that aircraft.
锁定目标
Target locked.
不要
Stop!
如果你毁了这艘飞船
If you destroy this ship...
就是毁了氪星
...you destroy Krypton!
氪星本来还有机会的
Krypton had its chance.
莲恩小姐 这儿不安全
Miss Lane! It's not safe for you...
离开那儿
...over there!
莲恩小姐
Miss Lane!
离开 快
Move now! Go!
死得光荣
A good death...
就是死得其所
...is its own reward.
他们走了吗？
Are they gone?
我想是的
I think so.
他救了我们
He saved us.
他们说初吻之后就每况愈下了
You know, they say it's all downhill after the first kiss.
我很确定 他们只统计了亲吻人类的数据
I'm pretty sure that only counts when you're kissing a human.
看这个
Look at this.
我们本可以在这片废墟上建立起一个新的氪星
We could have built a new Krypton in this squalor.
但是在我们和人类之间 你选择了后者
But you chose the humans over us.
我的存在
I exist...
仅是为了守护氪星
...only to protect Krypton.
这是自我出生以来的唯一目的
That is the sole purpose for which I was born.
我所做的一切
And every action I take...
无论多暴力
...no matter how violent...
多么残忍
...or how cruel...
皆是为了我的人民的福祉
...is for the greater good of my people.
现在
And now...
我没有人民了
...I have no people.
是你夺走了我的灵魂
My soul that is what you have taken from me.
我要让他们承担痛苦
I'm going to make them suffer, Kal.
你救下的人类 我要从你手里...
These humans you've adopted, I will take them all from you...
- 一个一个夺走   - 你这个怪物 佐德
- ...one by one.       - You're a monster, Zod...
我会阻止你的
...and I'm gonna stop you.
结束这一切只有一个办法
There's only one way this ends, Kal.
不是你死
Either you die...
就是我亡
...or I do.
我被当做一个战士训练
I was bred to be a warrior, Kal.
我终生都在受训控制感官
Trained my entire life to master my senses.
你在哪受训的？农场吗？
Where did you train? On a farm?
如果你深爱着这群人类
If you love these people so much...
就为他们追悼吧
...you can mourn for them.
不要
Don't do this!
住手
Stop!
不
不可能
Never.
你他妈是蠢蛋吗？
Are you effing stupid?
你有那么多空中侦察机
It's one of your surveillance drones.
这玩意值1200万
That's a $12,000,000 piece of hardware.
曾经值
It was.
我知道你想追踪我
I know you're trying to find out where I hang my cape.
- 但是没门   - 那我明确问你一个问题
- You won't.       - Then I'll ask the obvious question:
我们怎么知道有一天 你不会损害美国的利益？
How do we know you won't one day act against America's interests?
我在堪萨斯长大 将军
I grew up in Kansas, general.
我也算是美国人了
I'm about as American as it gets.
看
Look...
我愿意帮忙
...I'm here to help...
但必须是我心甘情愿
...but it has to be on my own terms.
你可以这样说服华盛顿
You have to convince Washington of that.
就算我愿意说 你认为他们会听吗？
Even if I were willing to try, what makes you think they'd listen?
不知道 将军
I don't know, general.
但是我只能相信你
Guess I'll just have to trust you.
- 你笑什么 上尉？  - 没什么 长官
- What are you smiling about?       - Nothing, Sir.
我觉得他帅爆了
I just think he's kind of hot.
- 上车 上尉   - 遵命
- Get in the car, captain.       - Mm-hm. Yes, sir.
他一直坚信你生来要做大事的
He always believed you were meant for greater things.
当这一天来临时
And that when the day came...
你的肩膀要能扛起千斤
...your shoulders would be able to bear the weight.
是啊 我希望他能够看到这一切
Yeah, I just wish he could have been here to see it finally happen.
他看到了 克拉克 相信我
He saw it, Clark, believe me.
你不拯救地球的时候 想干点什么？
What are you going to do when you're not saving the world?
- 有想过吗？ - 想过 真的
- Have you given any thought to that?       - I have, actually. Heh, heh.
我会找一份工作 能够保持高度警觉
I gotta find a job where I can keep my ear to the ground.
人们不会多看我两眼
Where people won't look twice...
当我要去危险的地方 不会问我问题
...when I want to go somewhere dangerous and start asking questions...
行行好 露易丝 你什么时候能可怜我一下呢？
Come on, Lois. When are you gonna throw me a bone?
今晚比赛的绝佳位子 怎么样？
Courtside seats to the game tonight.
- 什么？ - 我说...
- What do you say?       - I say...
你应该去钓钓实习生
...you should go back to trolling the intern pool.
可能会有好运 抱歉
You'll probably have more luck. Sorry.
看比赛？
Courtside?
- 别去   - 不去
- Don't. Ha, ha, ha.       - No.
伦巴第 莲恩 来见见新的特约通讯员
Lombard, Lane, I want you to meet our new stringer.
你给他传授传授窍门 他叫卡拉克•肯特
I want you to show him the ropes. This is Clark Kent.
好运 孩子
Good luck, kid.
我叫斯蒂夫
Hey. Steve.
- 幸会   - 幸会
- Nice to meet you.       - You too.
嗨
Hi.
我叫露易丝•莲恩
Lois Lane.
欢迎来《星球日报》
Welcome to the  Planet.
很高兴来这 露易丝
Glad to be here, Lois.